Darren Alexander Muliawan

504 Citadelle Ln, San Jose, CA 95116 • (424) 386-8322 • darrenalexandermuliawan@gmail.com

Education

University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign

August 2017 – May 2019

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science & Statistics

- Relevant Coursework: Software Design Studio, System Programming, Algorithms & Models of Computation, Database Systems, Data Mining, Art and Science of Web Programming, Statistics Programming Methods, Methods of Applied Statistics, Statistical Computing
- Academic Standing: GPA 3.69

Diablo Valley College

August 2015 - May 2017

Pleasant Hill, California

• Academic Standing: GPA 3.84

Summary of Qualifications

Proficient in C, C++, Java, Python, SQL and R programming language.

Experienced with Git, GitHub, HTTP Requests, REST Protocols, MongoDB, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Express, HTML, SASS, CSS, Django, R Shiny, Android Studio, Firestore, and Firebase.

Easy going and talkative person, but also a serious, hard worker, and a quick learner.

Work Experience

University of Illinois, Urbana – Champaign

June 2018 – August 2018

Data Analyst & Content Writer Intern, Student Money Management Center

- Collect the number of open rates and click rates from newsletters that were sent on previous weeks/months
- Create graphs to compare the open rates and click rates of the newsletter on specific topics or days of the week
- Suggest and discuss with other team members about what contents should be included for the next newsletters based on the information that we have gathered

Axioo, Surabaya, Indonesia

June 2017 – August 2017

Software Engineer Internship

- Team up and coordinated with the Android Developer Team
- Develop their new customized Android application for a manufacturing company in Surabaya, Indonesia
- Use Android Studio to design the user interface and SQLite to manage the company's inventory

Projects

Lost and Found

Spring 2019

- Create a full-stack web application for Lost and Found
- Designed and developed frontend application using React.js and Semantic UI
- Designed and developed backend API and database models using Node.js, Express, and MongoDB

Who Will Carry

Fall 2018

- Scraped the data frame from a website which contains performances of professional players in League of Legends from several season and region
- Clean the data from scraped tables to remove unreliable or missing values
- Create algorithms to calculate each player's value to team based on their position and performances
- Visualize the data in graphs and table in Shiny app

NCAA Fantasy Invest

Fall 2018

- Worked with a team of four to create a web application for investing in NCAA Basketball players.
- Designed and developed frontend application using React and Material UI
- Designed backend API and database models using Python, Django, Pandas and SQLite